is think about what the vision of an
opio is a vision of something this kind
of architecture and it's something we
kind of touched on here and there in all
the videos but that again that is the
this architecture is in the book we call
it a source code for an emerging culture
so this would be the vision the very
large vision of creating opie O's is
looking at a better world than seeing an
emerging culture and so the way I look
at it is in traditional society or
current society there's a sense in which
where there's a whole series of
constraints and we talked about this in
the previous video and the whitest
constraint is the governance right so
the government sets constraints the
government doesn't really set
possibilities anymore there's more of a
sense that its regulatory sets
constraints it has its own federal
agenda and within that we have the
financial system of investors and
venture capital and grants and
government and there's there's a lot of
pressure and constraints and lack of
flexibility and fluidity between the
government and the financial system the
financial system then the corporations
are heavily now depended upon the
financial system there's this whole
critique of virtual production cycles in
the financial system has become
something that has really constrained
corporations so we have a lot of
responsibility to investors and venture
capitalists and just kind of absentee
shareholders so this is the level of
corporation and the corporation may have
subsidiaries and because the
subsidiaries are not under the
pressure but the corporation's the
parent corporations of the parent
corporations have to pass on this
pressure to the subsidiaries and of
course each subsidiary within the each
organization with its subsidiary then
creates its architecture to be
constrained by these pressures on and on
and on and on until the individual in
here can imagine something that's open
and participatory but there's all this
contraction going into the daily and
ordinary life of this individual or this
team so that seems to me to be the
contraction of let's say a very mature
or late stage capitalist society with a
representational government not a
participatory one so this is a very big
and broad stroke but I think that we all
feel this the individual entrepreneur at
this level feeling all this pressure is
really at doesn't really have the
Liberty to liberate the employee because
there's all these other constraints that
the employee is not directly involved in
so the whole system kind of works as a
system of nested invariant structures
that's not and what makes them invariant
is the same as saying they're not
responsive so we don't see in here an
opportunity for any synergistic
participation
so with the Opio envisions in terms of
an emerging culture and we'll haven't
gotten to it but we look at the
governance here the endothermic
governance in the center it says if
instead of having the government or
governance being this top-down
constraint it's a participatory
governance and so if you think of let's
say the water the ocean level and this
is the water level and here is the
larger culture or the larger society
instead of government coming down and
constraining what we have is a cup is
participation of many streams right all
this little local participation that
bubbles up and co evolves a governance
right inside an organization and there
are many of these right so there's many
governance and many participatory
organizations many groups of people
participating together co-evolving the
governance the inside right at the heart
of this these organizations and then the
governance describes because when we get
to the government's will see the
governance describes defines and
delineates what what the performance
zones are the objectives and the values
in the performance zones and the
objectives and the values in the network
performance zones and there's a process
by which that evolves over time so the
governance makes possible the
delineation of these core performance
value zones right the governance is
where we describe define and design the
core performance value zones that create
value inside the organization and wealth
in the culture and then what we have is
the network value zones that start
to bubble up so this is like bubbling up
because the network performance value
zones have an inside and this
synergistic relationship to the outside
so they start to perform in the larger
culture above this let's say water level
and as those are that synergistic
participation happens then it's as if
this value that's created right so this
this organization value I say gets
exported as wealth into the culture in
these these extra organizational values
like support adaptation access and can
be incubation they become part of the
wealth of the culture so I like to see
these bubbles as if they start to rise
up from the organization into the larger
culture and it's not just from one
organization but it's from many
organizations right so it's a way for
the locus of cultural transformation to
come from inside the locus of production
and these these open participatory
organizations become the leading edge
supporting the export of wealth to the
cultural Commons and eventually what
happens is people become capable of
enacting participatory governance and
that is the biggest wealth in the
commons the Commons then becomes capable
of enacting a participatory governance
so that's the larger vision of the Opie
oh and there's a lot of work to be done
between now in this future vision but I
think it's exciting and can be really
fun